nflrush.com 2014-12-04

# NFLRUSH Privacy Policy

**Updated as of July 25, 2014**

The NFLRUSH website (the "Website") is new and improved! We have added new games, activities and features, including within the NFLRush Zone, to the site for your enjoyment and learning. We encourage you to read and understand our newly updated privacy policy as your privacy is important to us. 

The owners (The National Football League Enterprises, its respective representatives and subsidiaries, on behalf of the National Football League) and producers (Brandissimo!, Inc.), collectively referred to in this Privacy Policy as "we," "us" and "our," of the Website respect your privacy rights and recognize the importance of protecting the Personal Information (as defined below) provided by you and/or your child to the NFL and its representatives and/or subsidiaries. 

This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, store, and use the Personal Information you provide in conjunction with using the Website through telephone or e-mail communications you may have with the Website and our mobile applications. The Website has been awarded TRUSTe's Children's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability, and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadble software. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative solutions. This privacy statement covers the sites www.nflrush.com and the subdomain, www.nflrz.nflrush.com. Because the Website wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to discloseits information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact [nflrushprivacy@nfl.com](mailto:nflrushprivacy@nfl.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can [contact TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). 

This Privacy Policy also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of the Personal Information you and/or your child provide to the Website or the mobile applications of the Website (i.e., NFL Pick Em and NFLRush Fantasy). and the actions that can be taken to access this information and request the information you and/or your child provides be corrected or deleted. 

_About the Website_

The NFL has developed the Website, its own virtual world for kids, in order to give kids of all ages the chance to interact with the NFL in an innovative and entertaining way. The Website allows kids to play dozens of games, represent their favorite NFL Teams, explore 32 unique team lands, watch animated content, customize their avatars in myriad ways, buy and trade using virtual currency, chat and compete with other users in a safe manner, and more. Furthermore, good health and fitness are strongly enforced throughout the Website, and kids can enjoy the game year-round, with no prior football knowledge required. 

This Privacy Policy contains the following sections:

  * Children's Online Privacy and Protection Act Compliance
  * Consent
  * Information Collection
  * Other Information Collected
  * Information Sharing and Disclosure
  * Choice and Opt-Out
  * Access
  * Links to Other Websites
  * Storage and Security of Personal Information
  * International Transfer
  * Changes to this Privacy Policy
  * Questions and Comments
  * Contact Information

### Children's Online Privacy and Protection Act Compliance

The Children's Online Privacy and Protection Act of 1998 requires websites that store data from users under thirteen years old to inform parents about data storage policies and obtain parental permissions. Once given, parents may revoke those permissions at any time informing us of their decision. We strictly adhere to these requirements and will make every effort to meet and exceed the requirements mandated by law. <http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/buspubs/coppa.shtm>. 

### Consent

By using the Website products and/or services, you acknowledge that you have read this entire Privacy Policy and you consent to the practices described herein with respect to collection, use and disclosure of the Personal Information you and/or your child ("you") provides. 

This represents the entire and exclusive Privacy Policy and it supersedes any earlier version. The Website the right to change this Privacy Policy in accordance with the terms herein at any time. We encourage you to visit this page often, review this Privacy Policy frequently, and remain informed about any changes to it. 

If, after review, you still have questions about any portion of this Privacy Policy, please contact us using the contact information provided at the bottom of this Privacy Policy. 

### Information Collection and Use

_Personal Information_

"Personal Information" means information that can identify a specific individual (including those under 13 years of age), such as your name, gender, address, phone number, e-mail address, or other contact information, whether at work or at home. Other information that we may collect, includes gender, age, first name, username and password that, in and of itself, is not personally identifiable. 

In all cases in which we collect Personal Information, we specifically describe what information is collected in order to provide you with the product, service, or feature you have requested. 

As described below, the Website, our representatives and/or subsidiaries collect Personal Information when you contact us, when parental consent is required, when you register, when you use any and all related products and services, when you submit a question or purchase products and/or services offered for sale, when you visit websites of certain NFL partners, and when you enter promotions and sweepstakes. 

We do not save any Personal Information from users under thirteen-years-old except their parent's email address. We collect an e-mail address from each user in the registration process which protects the site from spam "bots" that search out and attack unprotected registrations. Our registration process delivers an e-mail to the registering user and then immediately and permanently deletes the email address of anyone under thirteen years of age. In the case where a user contacts us via the "Contact Us" area of the Website, we will respond to this one-time email and delete any email address that is associated with a user under the age of 13. 

We may collect your geo-location information for the purpose of setting your clock for the game feed, otherwise we do not ask for, access, or track any location based information from your mobile device. 

_Registration for The Website & Mobile Applications_

You are required to register in order to use selected features of the Website such as being able to customize your website experience. 

In order to register, you must first complete the online registration form, which requires that you create a username and password. During registration, you are also required to provide Personal Information, such as your e-mail address, gender and birth date, so that we may contact you about the services on the site(s) in which you have expressed interest and so that we may verify your age. 

Certain functionality of the Website may require parental notice or consent for children under 13 years of age in order to comply with the Children's Online Privacy and Protection Act. When a registrant indicates they are under 13 years of age, we will only collect first name, gender, parent's email address and birth date. Parent's of under 13 years of age users will be sent a parental notice indicating their child's wish to join the Website, information about the activities on the Website, disclosure of the information collected from the child including username and password, as well as instructions for the parent to delete membership. The full privacy policy is also included in this notice. In such instances where parental consent is needed, we will direct you to a web page explaining the procedure for obtaining parental consent. Features of the Website that require parental consent for children under 13 include, but are not limited to, the following: 

  * Permission to post a photo, artwork, video or essay that your child has submitted
  * Permission to enter you in a contest, sweepstakes or promotion
  * Permission to allow us to use your personal information to market the Website features and products directly to you.

Children under age 13 that choose to participate in the above site activities will be asked to provide their first name only and the email address of a parent to obtain parental consent. Please note that a child's participation or access to an activity cannot be conditioned on him/her providing more Personal Information than is reasonably necessary for that activity. 

Through our NFL Rush Zone app users are only able to view instructions, play games, view high scores, view games played, and enter their name (first name or username only) to be part of a leader board. 

Additionally, during the registration process you may be given the choice to opt-in to receiving additional related communications from the Website and the NFL. If you decide to opt-in, we will use the information provided to send you communications described throughout this Privacy Policy. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications (please see the "Choice and Opt-Out" section of this Privacy Policy) if at any time you decide you do not wish to receive such communications. Parents of users under thirteen years of age may also opt-in their child to receive additional related communications from the Website and the NFL. A parent can review, change or delete the Personal Information of their children at any time by emailing their children's username and parent's email address associated with the account, and their request, to us at [nflrushprivacy@nfl.com](mailto:nflrushprivacy@nfl.com). 

If a child chooses to sign up for an upgraded membership to NFL Rush Zone, the child's parent will need to complete the purchase form and pay for the membership using their credit card. Some of the payment methods accepted by the Website will require you to visit a trusted third party site. Please note that their privacy policy governs the collection and use of data while on their site. 

_Promotions, Contests and Sweepstakes_

The Website provides you the opportunity to participate in promotions, contests and/or sweepstakes on the Website. Such promotions, contests and sweepstakes are also governed by the rules and regulations posted with such promotions, contests and sweepstakes. You should refer to the specific games, promotions, contests and/or sweepstakes for the specific rules and regulations governing them. 

If you wish to participate, you will be required to register with the Website. If you are under 13 years old, your Parent will be asked to provide certain Personal Information so that you may be prize eligible. Participation in these promotions, contests and sweepstakes is completely voluntary and you and your parent have a choice whether or not to register and provide your Personal Information. The requested information typically includes contact information, such as name, shipping address, e-mail address, and telephone number. If your parent does not provide the Personal Information, you will be able to participate in the promotion, contest or sweepstakes but you will not be able to win any prizing. . We will use the Personal Information provided to us only to notify winners and award prizes, unless you (if over 13 years old) or your parent (if under 13) have opted in to receive marketing messages from the NFL. 

_Message Boards and Forums_

All users may read and post comments to our message boards and forums, such as The Buzz and NFL Play 60, without having to register. All comments that are submitted are reviewed prior to posting and any comments containing personally identifiable information of any kind or inappropriate content will not be posted to the Website. There may be some areas of the Website where personal information is displayed, such as the names of contest winners or youth football participants, but this information will not be posted to the Website without prior consent from parent. To request removal of your personal information from these areas of the site, contact us at [nflrushprivacy@nfl.com](mailto:nflrushprivacy@nfl.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

Users of the Website and our mobile applications may use the chat functionality within the Website and the commenting features within the mobile applications. All chat and comment functionality is moderated. We take every precaution that we can to prevent users from being able to provide personal information about themselves, however if you are posting within the Website or mobile applications please read above for how your information may be made publicly available. 

_Special Offers and Updates_

In certain instances, we will use your personal information to send you (or your parent) information about the Website features and products and other relevant offers, promotions, contests and sweepstakes that may interest you. If a user is under 13 years of age, the marketing materials will be sent to the parent's e-mail address that was provided by their child upon registration, and to the child if his/her parent has opted their child in to receive such messaging as stated above. If a user (or user's parent) no longer wishes to receive these marketing messages, a user can choose to opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each communication, or by e-mailing us at [nflrushprivacy@nfl.com](mailto:nflrushprivacy@nfl.com). A parent can also review, change or delete the Personal Information of their children at any time by emailing their children's username and parent's email address associated with the account, and their request, to us at [nflrushprivacy@nfl.com](mailto:nflrushprivacy@nfl.com). 

_Service-related Announcements_

The Website may, but is not obligated to send you strictly service-related announcements on occasions when it is necessary to do so. For example, if service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we may send you an e-mail. Generally, you will have the option to opt-out of these communications even though they are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive these types of communications you have the option to deactivate your account, or to opt-out (please see the "Choice and Opt-Out" section of this Privacy Policy). 

_Research_

The Website also collects non-personally identifiable information for research purposes and to provide anonymous reporting for internal and external purposes. We use the information collected for internal marketing and demographic studies, to improve customer service and to provide better service and product offerings. 

_Customer Service_

Based upon the Personal Information you provide, the Website, will send you a welcoming e-mail to verify your identity (including your username and password). We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. Generally, we will only communicate with you by e-mail or telephone, in accordance with your wishes. 

_Preferences_

The Website stores information we collect through cookies, log files, and third party sources to create a profile of your preferences, in order to improve the content of the site for you. 

### Other Information Collected

Some information may be collected automatically every time you visit the Website, such as cookies and other identifiable and non-identifiable computer information. In addition, information may be collected from other independent, third-party sources. The Website also collects information about which pages you visit within the website. This site visitation data is generally identified only by a unique URL. 

_Cookies_

The Website may use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies as part of its interaction with your browser. 

A cookie is an alphanumeric identifier (a file) that can be used to transfer data and personally identifiable information to and from your computer's hard drive through a Web browser to enable computing systems to recognize your browser for record-keeping purposes. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser, while a persistent cookie may remain on your hard drive for an extended period of time. 

The Website uses session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate the site. The Website uses persistent cookies to identify and track which sections of the site you most often visit. The Website also uses persistent cookies in areas of the site where you must register, and where you are able to customize the information you see, so that you do not have to enter your preferences more than once. These cookies do not collect Personal Information and we do not combine information collected through cookies with other Personal Information collected to determine your identity, your e-mail address or other personally identifiable information, including information regarding those under the age of 13. 

By configuring the options in your browser, you may control how cookies are processed by your system. However, if you decline the use of cookies you may not be able to use certain features of the Website, and you may be required to re-enter the information required to use site during new or interrupted browser sessions. 

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers, representatives and/or subsidiaries) may use cookies on the Website. 

THE WEBSITE DOES NOT DISCLOSE ITS COOKIES TO THIRD PARTIES EXCEPT AS REQUIRED BY A VALID LEGAL PROCESS SUCH AS: SEARCH WARRANT, SUBPOENA, JURISDICTIONAL STATUTE, OR COURT ORDER. 

_Log Files_

As is true of most websites, the Website gathers certain information automatically and stores it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet services provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and click-stream data. 

The Website uses this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the game and/or the website, to track users' movements and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. 

We do not combine information collected through log files with other Personal Information collected to determine your identity or personally identifiable information such as your e-mail address. 

_Web Beacons and Other Tracking Technology_

The Website uses a variety of technical methods for tracking purposes, including Web beacons. Web beacons are small pieces of data that are embedded in images on the pages of Web sites. We also use these technical methods to analyze the traffic patterns on our Web sites, such as the frequency with which our users visit various parts of our Web sites. These technical methods may involve the transmission of information either directly to us or to another party authorized by us to collect information on our behalf. We also use these technical methods in HTML e-mails that we send our guests to determine whether our guests have opened those e-mails and/or clicked on links in those e-mails. The information from use of these technical methods may be collected in a form that is personally identifiable. 

We use mobile analytics within our mobile applications which may track picks, track when a team logo is clicked on, game chats, and when someone clicks on an ad. The type of information being tracked is anonymous. 

_Information from Third Party Sources_

To improve services and enhance personalization, the Website may periodically obtain information about you from other independent third party sources and add it to our account information. 

### Information Sharing and Disclosure

The Website does not sell or rent any of the information collected to third parties in ways other than described in this policy. This includes any personal information of those under the age of 13. If we did share this type of information with third parties, as a parent, you would have the right to consent to the site's use of the child's Personal Information without having to consent to its disclosure of that information to third parties. Below are ways in which we do share your Personal Information: 

_Service Providers_

The Website may disclose the information (including that of those under the age of 13) collected to external service providers necessary to facilitate the following outsourced operations: address verification, credit card processing, web site hosting, email fulfillment, and product and/or service delivery. These external service providers are subject to confidentiality agreements with the Website, our representatives and/or subsidiaries and other legal restrictions that prohibit the use of the information we provide to them for any other purpose except to facilitate the specific outsourced operations listed above. 

_Compliance with Legal Authorities_

Your personal information, including that of children under the age of 13, may be transferred to third parties without notice to you in order to comply with applicable law, to cooperate with law enforcement agencies as required by a valid legal process (court order, subpoena), to protect our rights, or to protect the rights of other users of the Website. 

_Business Transfers_

In the event that all or substantially all of our or the Website's assets are sold or transferred to another party, or another transaction occurs in which your personally identifiable information is one of the business assets transferred, all personally identifiable information, including that of those under the age of 13, that has been collected and saved may be one of the business assets we transfer. You will be notified of such a transfer in accordance with the "Changes to the Policy" section below. 

If you have any inquiries regarding our partner's privacy practices or how they use your child's personal information, please contact us directly at [NFLPrivacy@nfl.com](mailto:NFLPrivacy@nfl.com). 

### Choice and Opt-Out

We provide you with the opportunity to opt-in to having your Personal Information used for certain purposes, when you are asked for this information. For example, if you purchase a service or product you must indicate that you wish to receive additional marketing materials from the NFLRUSH website, our representatives and/or subsidiaries, such as e-mails regarding special offers, promotions, and sweepstakes ("opt-in"). 

We provide you with the opportunity to choose having your Personal Information used for certain purposes, when you are asked for this information. For example, if you enter a contest or access certain features on the site, we may ask if you would like to receive additional marketing materials from us such as e-mails regarding special offers, promotions, and sweepstakes. 

If you do not wish to receive promotional communications, you may "opt-out" of receiving them by following the instructions included in each communication, or by e-mailing us at [nflrushprivacy@nfl.com](mailto:nflrushprivacy@nfl.com) or [nflrushsafety@nfl.com](mailto:nflrushsafety@nfl.com). 

### Access to Your Information

Parents of users under age 13 who provide consent for NFLRush to collect, use or disclose the Personal Information of their children may request to refuse further collection and use, review, change or delete the Personal Information of their children collected on the site by emailing their children's username and their request, to us at [nflrushprivacy@nfl.com](mailto:nflrushprivacy@nfl.com) or [nflrushsafety@nfl.com](mailto:nflrushsafety@nfl.com). All registered users including parents of those under the age of 13 may contact us at [nflrushprivacy@nfl.com](mailto:nflrushprivacy@nfl.com) to have their or their child's information removed, changed, or registration deleted or to request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forums. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

We will retain yours or your child's information for as long as yours or your child's account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at the email address listed above. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

### Links to Other Websites

There may be places throughout the Website that may link you to other websites that do not operate under this Privacy Policy. When you click through to these websites, this Privacy Policy no longer applies. 

_Chat Rooms, Forums, and Message Boards_

The Website includes a highly restrictive chat feature that prevents users from sharing their Personal Information with others. Several measures have been taken to prevent users from abusing the chat feature in an effort to share their Personal Information or to harass other users on the site. For example, when using this feature, users cannot type the following: 

  * Numbers (phone numbers, zip codes, residence numbers, etc.)
  * Proper Names (with the exception of NFL Team Names, etc.)
  * Geographical Locations (city, state, street names, etc.)
  * Email addresses
  * Explicit words

The chat feature is also monitored regularly by Website administrators to ensure that users communicate with others in a safe and respectful manner. In the event that someone is found to be abusing the chat feature, users can report the misconduct to the Website administrators, who will then take appropriate action. Reported users may be suspended or banned from the site. 

The use of the Website and all forums therein are governed by the Terms of Use, a copy which can be found in the footer at <http://accounts.nflrush.com/web/manage>, which is hereby incorporated by reference. In the event there exists any inconsistency between this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use, regarding the use of information, the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy shall take precedent. 

We reserve the right to terminate your membership with the Website in the event you use the Website, including, without limitation, the forums, in a manner inconsistent with the Terms of Use. 

### Storage and Security of Personal Information

_Storage_

The Website stores the information we collect on computers located in a controlled, secure facility protected from physical and/or electronic unauthorized access, use, or disclosure.

_Security_

We protect the privacy and integrity of the information collected by employing appropriate administrative protocols, technical safeguards, and physical security controls designed to limit access, detect and prevent the unauthorized access, improper disclosure, alteration, or destruction of the information under our control. We transmit the information used by external service providers for the specific outsourced operations listed above across public and private networks via recognized encryption technologies, such as by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts the information you input.

Although we follow the procedures set forth above to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Thus, while the Website, our representatives and/or subsidiaries strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security, please feel free to contact us.

_Internet Fraud_

We have a Zero Tolerance policy for Internet fraud or any attempt to access or acquire customer and/or other information via illegal or surreptitious means. We work with local, national, and international fraud investigation agencies as required and employ a variety of electronic and other means to discourage, detect, and intercept fraudulent activities.

We will aggressively prosecute to the fullest extent of the law those perpetrators apprehended who conduct fraudulent activities. Agencies with which the Website, our representatives and/or subsidiaries cooperate include (but are not limited to) state and local police authorities, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, US and International Customs Agencies, and Interpol.

_Email Abuse_

We have a Zero Tolerance policy for e-mail abuse. Our e-mail and e-mail list administrators take strong measures to ensure that any and all of our mailing lists are NOT used for abusive purposes. Further, our e-mail mailing list administrators maintain an "Ignore List" of e-mail addresses from which all information inquiries are ignored. E-mail addresses are added to the Ignore List when our e-mail mailing list administrators receive abusive or otherwise inappropriate email from listed e-mail addresses.

Personal Information collected by the Website may be stored and processed in the United States and/or any other country in which the NFL or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using other NFL websites, properties, products and/or services, you consent to any such transfer of Personal Information outside of your country.

### International Transfer

Personal Information collected by the NFLRUSH website may be stored and processed in the United States and/or any other country in which the NFL or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using other NFL websites, properties, products and/or services, you consent to any such transfer of Personal Information outside of your country.

**YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

**California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of the National Football League who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, pleasecontact us, or write us at CA Privacy Rights, NFL.com, 345 Park Ave, New York, NY 10154.**

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We will from time-to-time update this Privacy Policy, each time revising the last updated date at the top of the Privacy Policy and indicate the nature of the revisions within the statement. We will notify customers of material changes to this statement by e-mail or by placing prominent notice on the homepage of the Website. If we make material changes to how we use Personal Information collected from children under the age of 13, we will notify parents by email in order to obtain verifiable parental consent for the new uses of the child's Personal Information.

### Questions & Comments

If you have questions or suggestions regarding this Privacy Policy, you should first contact us using the contact information at the bottom of this Privacy Policy, and we will use all reasonable efforts to promptly determine and correct any problem(s).

### Contact Information

For technical support regarding use of the Website, please [contact us](http://nflrz.nflrush.com/footer/contactus).

For help regarding the Website safety and/or privacy and to respond to all parent's inquiries, please [contact us](http://nflrz.nflrush.com/footer/contactus).

Additionally, you may write to us at:

NFL Rush Safety & Privacy  
Attn: NFL Legal Department  
345 Park Ave  
New York, NY 10154  
212-450-2000
